呃......。
Uh...
哦，我必须在完成这一切之前...
Oh, I have to finish all this before...
去蒸一下今晚的桌布吧。
Go and steam the tablecloths for tonight.
我要把天花板上的水渍刷掉。
I'm going to paint over that water stain in the ceiling.
嗯！嗯？
Huh!
咦？哦。
Huh? Oh.
比如说，今天下午？
Like, this afternoon?
- 五分钟！- 什么？
- Five minutes! - What?
你用的是哪种颜料？
Which paint did you use?
乔伊在这里？去摆桌子吧。他一定很饿了。
Joy is here? Go set the table. He must be hungry.
我们稍后再谈？
We talk later?
嘿，嘿！
Hey, hey!
谢谢你这样做。
Thank you for doing this.
你现在看起来真漂亮。
You look really pretty right now.
哦，你喜欢这个...
Oh, you like this...
这个火辣辣的摩尔蒙造型？
this hot Mormon look?
我只是现在告诉你，以防我妈说
I'm just telling you now in case my mom says
说你很胖之类的蠢话。
something dumb like you're fat or whatever.
我以为你说当她说
I thought you said when she says
就说明她很在乎。
shit like that, it means she cares.
嗨，伊夫林。
Hi, Evelyn.
- 王夫人！- 嘿，妈妈。
- Mrs Wang! - Hey, Mom.
我做的菜只够三个人吃。
I only cook enough food for three people.
现在我得多做一些了。
Now I have to cook more.
那是乔伊。她把贝琪带来了。
It's Joy. She brought Becky.
- 嗨！嗨，亲爱的！
- Hi! - Hi, honey!
嗨，王先生！
Hi, Mr Wang!
嗨，贝琪！谢谢你的到来。
Hi, Becky! Thank you for coming.
请叫我韦蒙。来，坐。
Please call me Waymond. Here, sit.
你知道，他不一定要留下来。
You know, he doesn't have to stay.
他是谁？
Who's he?
- 贝琪。- 贝基是个女人。
- Becky. - Becky's a she.
你知道我的。
You know me.
我总是把 "他 "和 "她 "弄混。
I always mix up 'he', 'she'.
在中文里，只有一个词--'ta'--如此简单。
In Chinese, just one word - 'ta' - so easy.
还有你们俩的穿着打扮。
And the way you two are dressed,
我敢肯定，我不是唯一一个叫他 "他 "的人。
I'm sure I'm not the only one calling him 'he'.
我是说她的 "他"。呃！我不知道。
I mean her 'him'. Ugh!
总之，我的英语很好，我们有谷歌。
Anyways, my English is fine and we have Google.
所以你不必来做翻译。
So you don't have to come and be a translator.
你留在这里。
You stay here.
而她可以走了。
And she can go.
听着，我真的认为这很奇怪，好吗？
Look, I honestly think it's weird, OK?
但贝基想帮忙。对吧，贝琪？
But Becky wants to help. Right, Becky?
当我和老人在一起的时候，我总是能学到一些东西。
I always learn something when I hang out with the elderly.
老人是很有智慧的。
Old people are very wise.
嗯。没关系的。
Hmm. It's OK.
我们会带着公公去开会。
We'll take Gong Gong with us to the meeting.
呃，你和贝基留在这里装饰。嗯？
Uh, you and Becky stay here and decorate. Hmm?
他在哪里？我什么时候能见到他？
Where is he? When can I meet him?
哼! 顾客。
Huh! Customers.
吃得快。
Eat fast.
- 妈妈。- 什么？
- Mom. - What?
妈妈，等一下。
Mom, just wait.
等，等，今天没时间等了。
Wait? Wait? No time to wait today.
就请你...
Just please...
乔伊，其他任何时候，我求你来吃饭
Joy, any other time, I beg you to come and eat
或者给我打电话什么的，但今天很忙。
or call me or anything, but today very busy.
妈妈，这就是字面上的意思，它总是这样。
Mom, this is literally what it's always like.
错误的白色油漆！
Wrong white paint!
我知道你没有一直喜欢贝基，OK，但...
I know you haven't always liked Becky, OK, but...
我喜欢贝琪。她是非常好的。
I like Becky. She is very nice.
你很幸运...
You are very lucky...
她是半个墨西哥人。
She's half Mexican.
哼!
Ugh!
- 哼! - 洗衣机里没有鞋子。
- Huh! - No shoes in washer.
打破了，你来赔，是吗？
Broken, you pay, yeah?
但公公，他的心受不了。
But Gong Gong, his heart cannot take it,
尤其是经过这么长时间的飞行。
especially after such a long flight.
你想让他大老远从中国来，就这样死去吗？
You want him to come all the way from China to die like that?
他不会死的。
He's not gonna die.
呜呼!
Ooh!
- 我怎么帮你呢？- 坚持住。我听不见你说什么。
- How can I help you? - Just hold on. I can't hear you.
- 坚持住。- 有什么可以帮你的吗？
- Just hold on. - How can I help you?
我是来拿一些衬衫的。
I'm here to pick up some shirts.
- 我大概打了三次电话。- 把你的票给我。
- I called, like, three times. - Give me your ticket.
- 嗯，嗯，是的。- 我帮你找。
- Mmm-hmm, yeah. - I find for you.
- 不，我有票。- 宝贝儿...
- No, I have the ticket. - Babe...
她只是要求它，因为那是，像。
She's just asking for it 'cause that's, like,
它的工作方式。
the way that it works.
他们不会读心术。
They don't read minds.
那就挂了吧！谢谢你。
Then hang up! Thank you.
我们已经在一起三年了。
We've been together for three years.
你不觉得公公会想知道吗？
Don't you think Gong Gong would want to know?
让他享受今晚的聚会吧。
Let him enjoy his party tonight.
是啊，你认为贝基会得到通过整个
Yeah, you think Becky's gonna get through
你认为贝琪会在整个派对上不介绍自己...
the whole party without introducing herself...
- 伊夫林！- 你见过贝琪吗？
- Evelyn! - Have you met Becky?
猜猜看谁的20美元又被机器吃掉了。
Guess whose $20 got eaten by the machine again.
韦蒙！顾客需要你！
Waymond! Customers need you!
好了，来了！
Alright, coming!
艾芙琳，你知道吗，我妻子曾经用过
Evelyn, you know, my wife used to wear
一模一样的香水，上帝保佑她的灵魂。
that exact same perfume, God rest her soul.
你今晚会来参加聚会吗？
Are you coming to the party tonight?
是的，我有我的票，就在这里。
Yeah, I got my ticket right here.
对不起。这里太拥挤了，所以我把一些搬到了楼上。
Sorry. It was too crowded here so I moved some upstairs.
我想那里的衣服会更开心。
I think the clothes are happier there.
看到了吗？他们在这里更快乐。
See? They're happier here.
没有更多的谷歌的眼睛！
No more Google eyes!
妈妈，我们能谈谈贝基吗？
Mom, can we please talk about Becky?
我还是不知道他的大脑在想什么。
I still don't know what his brain is thinking.
贝琪今晚到底能不能来？
Can Becky come tonight or not?
- 别再转移话题了。- 我没有。
- Stop changing the subject. - I'm not.
你知道，这就像我们的审计师。
You know, it's like our auditor.
她是个可怕的人。
She is a terrible person.
她一直针对社区里的华人。
She keeps targeting the Chinese in the community.
你知道，两年来的会议，
You know, two years of meetings,
她在我们的洗衣店上设置了一个留置权。
she puts a lien on our laundromat.
而你知道你父亲做了什么？
And you know what your father does?
他给她送饼干。
He brings her cookies.
每一天我都在战斗，我在战斗。
Every day I fight, I fight.
我为我们所有人而战。
I fight for all of us.
这里的每一天都是一场战斗。
Every day is a battle here.
哦，你的父亲，他不关心事情的方式... ...
Oh, your father, he doesn't care about the way things are...
我努力使我们的生活更容易、更简单。
I try to make our lives easier and more simple.
你应该早点告诉我。
You should have told me earlier.
这真是令人印象深刻。
That's really impressive.
伊夫林，你得看看里克的舞蹈。
Evelyn, you have to see Rick dance.
看，他知道所有的动作。
Look, he knows all of the moves.
贝基，我他妈要自杀了。
Becky, I'll fucking kill myself.
他想成为一个演员，就像你一样。
He wants to be an actor, just like you did.
? 只要把你的手
♪ Just put your hand
在我手中...
♪ In my hand... ♪
? 我们将通过永恒的旋转
♪ And we'll spin through eternity
# 生活可以是如此美味
♪ Life can be so delicious
美味...
♪ Delicious... ♪
啊，我喜欢这个！
Ah! I love this!
- 里克，你真了不起。
- Hey! - Rick, you're so terrific.
我知道。我知道，我只是...
I know. I just...
我只是不知道怎样才能更清楚地表达出来。
I just don't know how to be any fucking clearer.
就像她可以选择...
It's like she can choose -
要么你跟我去参加聚会
either you come to the party with me
而公公则永远感到羞愧
and Gong Gong is eternally ashamed
直到他忘掉这一切，然后死去
until he forgets it all and then he dies
或者你不和我一起去，然后他还是会死。
or you don't come with me and then he still dies.
什么？
What? Huh!
- 你在说什么？- 那是一个笑话。
- What are you saying? - That was a joke.
呃，这不是一个很有趣的笑话，亲爱的。
Uh, that's not a very funny joke, honey.
- 嘿，伙计们... - 这只是10美元。
- Hey, guys... - This is only $10.
我以为你们这些人的数学很好。
I thought you people were very good with math.
- 下次我再给你利息。- 伊夫林？
- Next time I give you interest. - Evelyn?
妈妈，妈妈...
Mom, Mom...
- 妈妈！妈妈！- 什么？
- Mom! Mom! - What?!
嗯！
Huh!
韦蒙！韦蒙！
Waymond! Waymond!
咦？
Huh?
哦！
Oh!
呒...
Uh...
呃... ...
妈的，你怎么说的？呃...
Shit, how do you say it? Uh...
哦！
Oh!
妈妈...
Mom...
你知道吗？我其实没有这样做。
You know what? I'm actually not doing that.
这就像在这一点上我不...
It's like at this point I do not...
很高兴见到你！
It was nice to meet you!
嗨！给我们五星级的清洁。
Hi! Give us five-star cleaning.
另外...
Also...
今晚有一个中国新年的聚会。
There is a Chinese New Year party tonight,
对社区内所有的顾客开放。
open to all the customers in the community.
谢谢你。
Thank you.
- 请来享受... - 这很好。
- Please come and enjoy... - This is fine.
- 好的食物... - 好的。
- The good food... - OK.
- 还有美妙的音乐，好吗？- 好的。
- And nice music, OK? - Alright.
我给你一个邀请。等一下... 等一下，请。
I get you an invite. Moment... moment, please.
- 你现在能听到这个吗？- 乔伊，等等！求你了！
- Can you hear this right now? - Joy, wait! Please!
我有话要对你说！
I have something to say to you!
什么？
What?
你...
You...
你必须尝试吃得更健康。
you have to try and eat healthier.
你越来越胖了。
You are getting fat.
伊夫林？
Evelyn?
艾芙琳？
走，走，走，走！
Go, go, go, go!
好了！
OK!
如果我今天再想一件事，
If I have to think of one more thing today,
我的头就会炸开。
my head will explode.
你可能处于严重的危险之中。
You may be in grave danger.
没有时间解释了。拿着这个。
There's no time to explain. Hold this.
你为什么要这样做？
Why are you doing this?
请注意。
Pay attention.
当我们离开这个电梯时，你可以向左转
When we leave this elevator, you can either turn left
向你预定的审计预约方向走
towards your scheduled audit appointment
或者你可以向右转，进入看门人的柜子。
or you can turn right and go into the janitor's closet.
我为什么要进入看门人的...
Why would I go into the janitor's...
不是现在。
Not now.
你为什么在我的手机上下载所有这些应用程序？
Why you download all these apps on my phone?
吸气。
Breathe in.
你会感觉到你的头部有轻微的压力。
You're gonna feel a slight pressure in your head.
嗯！
Huh!
嘿，宝贝乔伊！
Hey, baby Joy!
你给我回来！
You come back here!
闭嘴！
Shut up!
你不要这样跟你妈妈说话！
You don't talk to your mother like this!
我他妈的想怎么跟她说就怎么说！
I'll talk to her how I fucking want!
激活...
Activation...
在你进入会议的那一刻，
The moment you're situated in your meeting,
遵循这些指示。
follow these instructions.
但是，记住，不能让任何人知道。
But, remember, no-one can know.
甚至不要和我说这些
Don't even talk to me about this
因为我不会记得。
because I won't remember.
- 但我... - 嘘。
- But I... - Shh.
心理扫描完成。
Mental scan complete.
很快就会和你谈话。
Talk to you soon.
你好！
Hello!
王夫人？
Mrs Wang?
王夫人，你和我们在一起吗？
Mrs Wang, are you with us?
是的。
Yes.
当然了。我在这里。
Of course. I am here.
- 只是在想。- 哦，好的。
- Just thinking. - Oh, OK.
好吧，我只是希望...
Well, I was just hoping...
你能解释一下这个。
that you could explain this.
这是一张收据。
This is a receipt.
我的收据。
My receipt.
听着，我...
Look, I...
我只是希望你能给我一些启发
I was just hoping you could enlighten me
作为一个洗衣店老板，是如何做到的？
as to how, as a laundromat owner,
一台卡拉OK机
a karaoke machine
可以构成商业开支？
could constitute a business expense?
我是一个歌手。
I am a singer.
- 你当然是。- 这是真的。
- Of course you are. - It's true.
她有一个美丽的声音。哦!
She has a beautiful voice. Oh!
伊夫林，为她唱首歌吧。
Evelyn, sing a song for her.
- 嘘！- 不，不，请。
- Shh! - No, no, please.
这将是没有必要的。
That will not be necessary.
但我需要一个单独的附表C
But I will need a separate Schedule C
为每项业务单独列出
for each of these businesses
因为根据你想要扣除的内容，你也是一个小说家和厨师。
because based on what you're trying to deduct,
你也是一个小说家和一个厨师。
you're also a novelist and a chef.
上一次，你告诉我...
Last time, you told me that...
求你了。
Please.
一个老师。
A teacher,
呃，还有一个歌唱教练
uh, and a singing coach
和一个 "瓦特 "技师。
and a 'Watsu' technician.
我很抱歉。什么... 什么是 "Watsu"？
I'm sorry. What... what is 'Watsu'?
它是一种水按摩。
It's a water massage.
什么是水按摩？
What's a water massage?
比如... ... 比如治疗背痛。
Like... like for back pain.
你去做个水按摩。
You go get a water massage.
- 哦，你去？- 是的。
- Oh, you go? - Yes.
发生了什么事？
What's happening?
就像我在和我的前夫说话。
Like I'm talking to my ex-husband.
就像我之前对你说的那样，共同混合你的... ...
Like I said to you before, co-mingling of your...
- 是你在扰乱我的大脑。- 嘘！
- It's you messing with my head. - Shh!
- 别嘘我！- 你得放松你的身体。
- Don't shh me! - You got to relax your body.
不要...
Don't...
平静下来，请！
Calm down, please!
冷静下来。
Calm down.
在另一个宇宙中放松你的身体。求你了。
Relax your body in the other universe. Please.
这些推理...
These deductions...
进入自动驾驶状态。
Go into auto-pilot.
你不能再扣除它，如果它是一个关...
You can't then deduct it if it's an off...
好的。很好。
Good. Good.
他们还不知道你和我在这个宇宙中。
They don't know you and I are in this universe yet
所以，希望我有时间解释。
so, hopefully, I'll have some time to explain.
我不是你的丈夫。至少不是你认识的那个。
I am not your husband. At least not the one you know.
我是另一个版本的他
I am another version of him
来自另一个人生道路，另一个宇宙。
from another life path, another universe.
我来这里是因为我们需要你的帮助。
I'm here because we need your help.
今天非常忙。没有时间来帮助你。
Very busy today. No time to help you.
嘘!
Shh!
有一个巨大的邪恶已经在我的世界里扎根了
There is a great evil that has taken root in my world
并开始在众多经文中散布其混乱
and has begun spreading its chaos
遍及许多经文。
throughout the many verses.
我花了多年时间寻找
I have spent years searching
寻找一个人，他可能会用更大的善来匹配
for the one who might be able to match
以更大的善来匹配这个巨大的邪恶
this great evil with an even greater good
并带来平衡。
and bring back balance.
所有这些年的寻找将我带到了这里......
All those years of searching have brought me here...
- 王夫人？- ...来到这个宇宙。
- Mrs Wang? - ..to this universe.
- 喂？
- Hello?! - To you.
我知道现在要接受的东西很多... ...
I know it's a lot to take in right now...
王夫人？
Mrs Wang?!
喂？
Hello?
听着，我相信你有很多事情要考虑，但我无法想象有什么比这更重要。
Look, I'm sure you have a lot on your mind,
但我无法想象有什么事情会比我们现在的谈话更重要
but I cannot imagine anything mattering more
比我们现在的谈话更重要
than the conversation we are now having
关于你的纳税义务。
concerning your tax liability.
呃，需要我提醒你的是
Uh, need I remind you that there is
你的财产已经被留置了？
already a lien on your property?
收回财产是我们的权利。
Repossession is well within our rights.
我知道。我正在注意。
I know. I am paying attention.
你看到这些了吗？
Do you see these?
你没有得到其中的一个
You don't get one of these
除非你已经看到了很多的废话。
unless you've seen a lot of bullshit.
请原谅我的法语。
Excuse my French.
现在你可能...
Now you may...
只看到一堆无聊的表格和数字。
only see a pile of boring forms and numbers,
但我看到了一个故事。
but I see a story.
除了一叠收据，什么都没有。
With nothing but a stack of receipts,
我就能追踪到你们生活的起伏。
I can trace the ups and downs of your lives.
而这看起来并不美好。
And it does not look good.
它看起来并不好。
It does not look good.
- 但是......呃......
- But... - Uh...
对不起，我妻子把她的爱好和生意混淆了。
Sorry, my wife confuses her hobbies for businesses.
一个诚实的错误。
An honest mistake.
哦，好吧。
Oh! OK.
好吧，所有这些，嗯... ...
Well, with all of these, um...
"诚实的错误，"
"honest mistakes,"
我是说，即使我们不指控你欺诈，
I mean, even if we don't charge you with fraud,
我们也肯定要对你进行罚款
we'll most certainly have to fine you
严重过失。
for gross negligence.
你总是试图用这些大词来迷惑我们
You're always trying to confuse us
用这些大词来迷惑我们。
with these big words.
我以为你会带
I thought you were going to bring
你的女儿来帮你翻译。
your daughter to help you translate.
- 我是要带我的... - 嘿!
- I am going to bring my... - Hey!
- 对不起。- 伊夫林？
- Sorry. - Evelyn?
她要来...
She was going to come...
伊夫林！你注意到了吗？
Evelyn! Are you paying attention?
我现在不能说话。
I cannot talk now.
她太忙了，不能帮助她的父母？
She's too busy to help her parents?
除非你能帮我报税。
Unless you can help me with my taxes.
什么是 "毛项链"？
What is "gross necklaces"?
我知道你有很多事情要考虑。
I know you have a lot of things on your mind,
但没有什么能比我们的谈话更重要
but nothing could possibly matter more
比我们现在进行的对话
than this conversation we are having
现在关于我们无限的世界的命运
right now concerning the fate
我们无限的多元宇宙的每一个世界的命运。
of every single world of our infinite multiverse.
对长辈的尊重到哪里去了？
Where's the respect for elders?
我亲爱的伊夫林。
My dear Evelyn,
我了解你。
I know you.
随着时间的推移，
With every passing moment,
你担心你可能已经错过了你的机会
you fear you might have missed your chance
使你的生活有所作为。
to make something of your life.
我在这里要告诉你
I'm here to tell you
每一次被拒绝
every rejection,
每一次失望都让你来到这里
every disappointment has led you here
到这一刻。
to this moment.
不要让任何事情分散你的注意力。
Don't let anything distract you from it.
你觉得这很有趣吗？
Do you think this is funny?
那么会是什么呢？
So what will it be?
我在想。
I'm thinking.
我们在这里的时间到了。
Our time here is up.
- 他们会杀了我们。- 什么？
- They're going to kill us. - What?
你认为你可以给我们更多的时间，这样我们就可以重做这一切？
You think you can give us more time so we can redo all this?
不要担心，这只是一个燃烧器宇宙
Do not worry, this is just a burner universe
我们正在使用的通信。
we are using for communication.
哦--哦--哦!
Oh-oh-oh!
你会知道什么时候是战斗的时候。
You will know when it is time to fight.
你想重做？你要重新提交？
You want to redo? You're going to resubmit?
- 我很快就会和你联系。- 嘘，嘘，嘘。
- I will be in contact soon. - Shh, shh, shh.
我想我的另一个丈夫正在搞乱审计工作。
I think my other husband is messing up the audit.
也许我们可以再看看所有的收据，然后...
Maybe we can look at all the receipts again and...
伊夫林！不要相信任何人。哦！
Evelyn! Trust no-one. Oh!
哦，不，不。不，不，不，不。不...！
Oh, no, no. No, no, no. No...!
哦，亲爱的主啊。
Oh, dear lord.
好了。一切正常。
OK. Everything OK.
我想我忘了一些东西在家里。
I think I forget something at home.
呃，坐下来。
Uh, sit down.
我想我要后悔了。
I think I'm going to regret this.
你可以走了。
You can go.
什么？
What?
你... 你会有...
You... you will have...
你必须在我今晚离开办公室之前
You will have until I leave the office tonight
把所有东西都带过来，下午6点。
to bring everything in, 6:00 P.M.
最后的机会。
Last chance.
- 哦，明天会更好... - 谢谢你！谢谢你！谢谢你！
- Oh, tomorrow is better... - Thank you! Thank you!
谢谢你。下午6点
Thank you. 6:00 P.M.
- 非常感谢你。- 谢谢你的饼干。
- Thank you so much. - Thank you for the cookies.
它们看起来很好吃。
They look delicious.
最后一次机会！
Last chance!
祝你有个愉快的一天。
Have a nice day.
最后的机会。
Last chance.
哦，不。
Oh, no.
伊夫林！艾芙琳！
Evelyn! Evelyn!
那么你知道这事？
So you know about this?
是你。比如说，在电梯里的你。
It was you. Like, you who was in the elevator.
我当时在电梯里。
I was in the elevator.
下周再来吧。
Come back next week.
我还没准备好战斗。
I'm not ready to fight.
I am not ready to fight.
也许我们没有选择。
Maybe we don't have a choice.
什么？
What?
把鞋子换成什么？
Switch shoes to what?
- 嗷！艾芙琳？
- Ow! Oh! - Evelyn?!
谁来叫一下保安!
Someone call security!
你在做什么？
What are you doing?
你叫我这么做的！
You told me to do it!
你说过我会知道什么时候是战斗的时候!
You said I would know when it is the time to fight!
她正在追赶我们。
She was coming after us.
哦!
Oh!
哦，你不知道，女士。哦！
Oh, you have no idea, lady. Oh!
攻击一个国税局的工作人员？
Assaulting an IRS agent?
你根本不知道！
You have no idea!
"婚姻解体"？
"Dissolution of marriage"?
是的，我在十楼。
Yes, I'm on the tenth floor.
不...
No...
你哥哥离婚了。
Your brother gets a divorce,
现在你认为离婚可以吗？
now you think divorce is OK?
我不认为它是可以的！
I don't think it's OK!
我们做了一个神圣的承诺。
We made a sacred promise.
我告诉过你要保持低调，不要让人看到。
I told you to stay low and out of sight.
哦，现在你来了？
Oh, now you're here?
哼！别再迷惑我了，来了又走。
Huh! Stop confusing me, coming and going.
- 别闹了，别闹了，别...
- Stop it, stop it, stop... - Relax.
我会带你离开这里的。
I'll get you out of this.
不要再来这里了。
Stop coming here.
好了，伙计们。大家保持冷静。
OK, folks. Everyone remain calm.
哦，感谢... 感谢上帝！
Oh, thank... thank God!
是那边那个人。那个中国女人！
It's that one right there. The Chinese lady!
不，这都是他的错！
No! It's all his fault!
就在那里，她袭击了我！
Right there, she assaulted me!
好的，我需要你们两个趴在地上
OK, I need you two to get on the ground
双手放在脑后。
with your hands behind your heads.
好的，好的，好的。
OK, OK, OK.
先生，请遵守。
Sir, please comply.
好的，无论你想做什么，都不要做。
OK, whatever you're thinking about doing, don't do it.
先生？
Sir?
没问题。
It's OK.
好的，先生。这就够了。
OK, sir. That's enough.
哦！
Oh!
真他妈的。
Holy shit.
Hyah!
哦！
Oh!
嘿。
Hey.
哦，不，克雷格！操。
Oh, no, Craig! Fuck.
啊！
Arggh!
在你的脚。
On your feet.
谁... 发生了什么事？
Who... What is happening?
我不是那个想和你离婚的韦蒙。
I'm not the Waymond who wants to divorce you.
我是拯救你生命的韦蒙。
I'm the Waymond who is saving your life.
现在，你可以选择跟我走
Now, you can either come with me
发挥你的最终潜力
and live up to your ultimate potential
或者躺在这里，承受后果。
or lie here and live with the consequences.
我想躺在这里。
I want to lie here.
嘿，嘿，嘿。
Hey, hey, hey.
不，不！放我下来！不，不！
No, no! Put me down! No, no!
第4655届Thetaverse的公民们，
Citizens of the 4,655th Thetaverse,
你们即将被我们的领袖
you are about to be graced
我们伟大的领袖的出现。
by the presence of our sovereign leader,
乔布-图帕奇。
Jobu Tupaki.
现在让我向你们保证一件事。
Now let me assure you of one thing.
就像你们其余的悲惨生活一样。
Just like the rest of your miserable lives,
这不过是
this is nothing more
只是一种统计学上的不可避免性。
than a statistical inevitability.
鸭子。
Duck.
鸭子...
Duck...
乔布-图帕奇
Jobu Tupaki
见过所有的人，知道所有的事。
has seen all and knows all.
她知道是什么让你心动。
She knows what makes you tick,
你的自我价值建立在哪些脆弱的树枝上。
on what fragile branches your self-worth rests.
这一个。
This one.
坚持住。
Hang on.
先别死，好吗，伙计？
Don't die yet, alright, buddy?
呃。
Ugh.
这不是她。
It's not her.
警方正在寻找所有的信息。
Police are looking for all information.
这是一个发展中的故事。
This is a developing story.
- 我们所知道的是... - 他们可能很亲密。
- What we do know... - They might be close.
我们确实有未经证实的嫌疑人照片。
We do have unconfirmed photos of the suspects.
一名身份不明的男子
An unidentified man
在西米谷的国内税务局区域办公室发飙
went berserk at the regional office
今天上午，一名身份不明的男子在西米谷的国内税务局区域办公室发飙。
for the Internal Revenue Service in Simi Valley this morning.
警方没有公布任何信息...
Police aren't releasing any information...
- 这是你父母所在的地方吗？- 这是一个发展中的故事。
- Is that where your parents are? - This is a developing story.
- 但我们确实有未经证实的... - 你还好吗？
- But we do have unconfirmed... - Are you OK?
嫌疑人的照片。
Photos of the suspects.
- 如果你认得他们...
- If you recognise them... - Hey!
- 你还好吗？
- Are you OK? - ..help identify them.
乔伊？
Joy?
如果你认得这两个人，
If you recognise these two,
警方正在寻求帮助确认袭击者。
police are seeking help identifying the assailants.
我丈夫连蜘蛛都不杀。
My husband won't even kill a spider.
你怎么可能是同一个人？
How can you be the same person?
你低估了最微小的决定如何
You underestimate how the smallest decisions
可以在一生中复合成重大的差异。
can compound into significant differences over a lifetime.
每一个微小的决定都会产生
Every tiny decision creates
另一个分支的宇宙，另一个...
another branching universe, another...
你以前没有注意到吗？
Were you not paying attention before?
当然了。你只是非常不善于解释...
Of course. You're just very bad at explaining...
嘘！
Shh!
别推我！
Don't push me!
哦，我的上帝！我们得回去了。
Oh, my God! We have to go back.
我们忘了我的父亲！
We forgot my father!
别担心。我们正在监视他。他是安全的。
Don't worry. We're monitoring him. He's safe.
- 我不知道。你确定吗？- 是的。
- I don't know. Are you sure? - Yes.
嘿，看，来吧！
Hey, look, come on!
看，这是你的宇宙。
Look, this is your universe,
一个漂浮在宇宙存在泡沫中的气泡。
one bubble floating in the cosmic foam of existence.
每个周围的气泡都有轻微的变化。
Every surrounding bubble has slight variations.
但你离你的宇宙越远，
But the further away you get from your universe,
差异就越大。
the bigger the differences.
这就是我的家乡，阿尔法宇宙。
This is where I am from, The Alphaverse.
是第一个与其他宇宙接触的宇宙。
The first universe to make contact with the others.
你可以叫我Alpha Waymond。
You can call me Alpha Waymond.
在这个世界上
In this world,
你是个聪明的女人。
you were a brilliant woman.
在你寻求证明
In your search to prove
其他宇宙的存在
the existence of other universes,
你发现了一种方法，可以暂时将你的意识与另一个版本的自己联系起来
you discovered a way to temporarily link
你的意识与另一个版本的自己相联系。
your consciousness to another version of yourself,
获取他们所有的记忆。
accessing all of their memories,
他们的技能，甚至他们的情绪。
their skills, even their emotions.
就像你带着芬尼包？
Like you with the Fanny pack?
没错。这就是所谓的 "诗句跳跃"。
Exactly. It's called Verse Jumping.
"诗句跳跃"。
"Verse Jumping."
我需要你现在就学会怎么做。
I need you to learn how to do it right now.
现在？
Right now?!
这可能是我们活着离开这里的唯一机会。
It may be our only chance of getting out of here alive.
两个守卫朝这边走来。
Two guards coming this way.
听我的信号，尽量混进去。
On my signal, try to blend in.
你为什么不叫你的伊夫林来做这个？
Why don't you get your Evelyn to do this?
我的伊夫林已经死了。
My Evelyn is dead.
走吧！哦，我的上帝！
Go! Oh, my God!
哦，我的上帝，发生了什么事？
Oh, my God, what is going on?
救救我们！救救我们！
Help us! Help us!
我是怎么死的？
How did I die?
我见过你有一千种死法。
I've seen you die a thousand ways,
在一千个世界里。
in a thousand worlds.
在每一个世界里，你都是被谋杀的。
In every single one, you were murdered.
什么？为什么会有人想杀我？
What? Why would anybody want to kill me?
她是一个无所不在的生命，拥有无法想象的力量。
She's an omniversal being with unimaginable power,
一个纯粹的混沌的代理人，
an agent of pure chaos,
没有真正的动机或欲望。
with no real motives or desires.
- 乔布-图帕奇。- 你只是在捏造声音。
- Jobu Tupaki. - You're just making up sounds.
嘘！
Shh!
我们需要另一个出口。
We need another exit.
所以，让她摧毁其他的泡沫。
So let her destroy the other bubbles.
你说过有这么多的泡泡。
You said there are so many of them.
也许我们失去一些也没关系。
Maybe it's OK if we lose some,
但别把我扯进去。
but just leave me out of it.
这不是那么简单。
It's not so simple.
她一直在建造一些东西。
She's been building something.
我们以为它是某种黑洞。
We thought it was some sort of black hole.
但它似乎消耗了
But it appears to consume
不仅仅是光和物质。
more than just light and matter.
我们不知道它到底是什么。
We don't know exactly what it is.
我们不知道它是用来做什么的。
We don't know what it's for.
但我们都能
But we can all
感觉到它。
feel it.
你也感觉到了，不是吗？
You've been feeling it too, haven't you?
有些东西不对劲。
Something is off.
你的衣服在第二天从未穿得那么好。
Your clothes never wear as well the next day.
你的头发永远不会以同样的方式落下。
Your hair never falls in quite the same way.
甚至你的咖啡的味道...
Even your coffee tastes...
错了。
wrong.
我们的机构正在崩溃。
Our institutions are crumbling.
没有人再相信他们的邻居。
Nobody trusts their neighbour anymore.
你夜里不睡觉，想知道自己... ...
And you stay up at night wondering to yourself...
我们如何才能回到过去？
How can we get back?
这就是阿尔法宇宙的使命--
This is the Alphaverse's mission -
带我们回到它应该有的样子。
to take us back to how it's supposed to be.
但这要从找到一个
But that begins with finding the one
谁可以站在Jobu的反常的混沌笼罩下。
who can stand up to Jobu's perverse shroud of chaos.
你认为是我吗？
And you think it's me?
否则，为什么我们会冒着一切风险
Why else would we risk everything
为了让你离开这里？
to get you out of here?
哦，你在这里。
Oh, there you are.
哦，迪尔德丽小姐！
Oh, Miss Deirdre!
我很抱歉我打了你，但是...
I'm sorry I punched you, but...
听着。
Look.
我想我终于明白为什么...
I think I finally understand why...
她在做什么？
What is she doing?
节奏跳动。快跑！
Verse Jumping. Run!
- 来吧。- 哦！
- Come on. - Oh!
走！去吧！快走！
Go! Go! Go!
她跳到了某个地方。蛮力。
She jumped somewhere. Brute force.
那个相扑运动员？
The sumo wrestler?
- 健美运动员？- 无所谓了。
- Body builder? - Doesn't matter.
用敏捷的人反击。
Counter with someone agile.
在你的周围，我们有一个霹雳舞者，哑剧... ...
On your perimeter, we've got a break dancer, mime...
- 一个体操运动员。- 给我体操运动员！
- A gymnast. - Give me gymnast!
- 开始！- 计算路线。
- Go! - Calculating route.
好的，一些剪纸，有四个。
OK, some paper cuts, four of them.
每个手指之间有一个。
One between each finger.
剪纸只在你不努力的时候发生。
Paper cuts only happen when you aren't trying.
这是不可能的。
It's impossible.
概率 - 8,000分之一。
Probability - 1 in 8,000.
这是我们拥有的最强的跳板。
It's the strongest jumping pad we have.
- 你在做什么？- 来吧，来吧。
- What are you doing? - Come on, come on.
有了，一个。
There we go, one.
- 有两个。- 哦。
- There's two. - Ooh.
- Ugh! - 三。
- Ugh! - Three.
好吧，来吧，来吧，来吧。跟着我。
Alright, come on, come on, come on. Stick with me.
来吧。
Come on.
- 四！就在那里。
- Four! There it is.
好吧，来吧，跳！
OK, come on, jump!
嗯！
Huh!
那是职业摔跤吗？
Is that pro wrestling?
她要来个背摔！
She's going for a backbreaker!
- 她得跑了。- 不。
- She's gotta run. - No.
她可以跳下去，在某个地方可以打。
She can jump, somewhere she can fight.
她还没准备好。
She's not ready.
这样的跳跃会把大多数人炸死。
A jump like that would fry most people.
她不是大多数人。
She's not most people.
该死的，多么虚弱的身体。
Damn, what a weak body.
- 艾芙琳！
- Hello? - Evelyn!
你能听到我吗？
Can you hear me?
你必须要跳伞。
You're going to have to Verse Jump.
Verse Jump?
喂？
Hello?
专注于一个宇宙
Concentrate on a universe
在其中你学习武术。
in which you studied martial arts.
好的，我正在锁定。
OK, I'm locking in.
计算完成。
Calculations complete.
"表白你的爱。"
"Profess your love."
你得向迪尔德丽表白你的爱。
You're gonna have to profess your love to Deirdre.
- 不可能。- 这是你的跳板。
- No way. - It's your jumping pad.
这就像吃口香糖或换鞋一样。
It's like eating the chapstick or switching shoes.
我们开发了一种算法，可以计算出
We developed an algorithm that calculates
哪个统计学上不可能的行动
which statistically improbable action
会把你放在一个宇宙中
will place you in a universe
在你的本地集群的边缘。
on the edge of your local cluster,
然后将你吊射到所需的宇宙。
which then sling shots you to the desired universe.
这没有任何意义!
That doesn't make any sense!
正是如此。
Exactly.
它的意义越小越好。
The less sense it makes, the better.
随机路径算法是由随机行动推动的。
The Stochastic Path Algorithm is fuelled by random actions.
告诉她你爱她，并且是认真的。
Tell her you love her and mean it.
还有其他跳板吗？
Are there any other jumping pads?
接下来的最佳路径是折断自己的手臂或打盹。
The next best paths are break your own arm or take a nap.
你不困，是吗？
You're not sleepy, are you?
我愛你。
I love you.
跳板失败。
Jumping pad failure.
伊夫林，等等！不！
Evelyn, wait! No!
不，不。
No.
她在一个局部分歧的宇宙中。
She's in a local divergent universe.
不，不，不。
No, no, no.
她已经回家了...
She's gone home...
去完成税收。
to finish the taxes.
啊！
Ah!
这没有任何意义。
This doesn't make any sense.
想一想吧。
Think about it.
你总是被拉走。
You always get pulled away.
Waymond！
Waymond!
韦蒙！韦蒙！
我很抱歉，艾芙琳
I'm sorry, Evelyn.
- 嗯？- 我得走了。
- Huh? - I need to go.
什么？
What?
我需要找到正确的伊夫林。
I need to find the right Evelyn.
而这个人..,
And this one,
它不是那个人。
it's not the one.
不，不。等等，让我再试试！
No! No. Wait, let me try again!
阿尔法-韦蒙德？
Alpha Waymond?
伊夫林？
Evelyn?!
- 哦。- 咦？
- Oh. - Huh?
啊！我的手怎么了？
Ah! What's happened to my hand?
走，走，走，走！
Go, go, go, go!
伊夫林，你的脸。
Evelyn, your face.
你刚刚离开了我。
You just left me.
你刚刚离开了我！
You just left me!
韦蒙...
Waymond...
迪尔德丽小姐？
Miss Deirdre?
- 我愛你！- 什么？
- I love you! - What?
我愛你！
I love you!
不，不！
No, no!
我愛你！
I love you!
我爱你！
我爱...
I love...
伊夫林！
Evelyn!
停，停，停，停！
Cut, cut, cut, cut!
哦，我很高兴今天能来这里。
Oh, I'm so happy to be here today.
- 伊夫林！- 伊夫林！伊夫林！
- Evelyn! - Evelyn!
伊夫林！伊夫林！
Evelyn!
哦！
Oh!
你为什么... 怎么会？
Why did you... How?
这很美。
It was beautiful.
韦蒙。
Waymond.
我们最好继续前进。
We better keep moving.
现在你肯定已经得到了Jobu的注意。来吧。
Now you've definitely got Jobu's attention. Come on.
保持冷静。
Stay calm.
你的大脑正承受着巨大的压力。
Your brain is under an incredible amount of stress.
不，让我完成与我的丈夫交谈。
No, let me finish talking with my husband.
他需要知道我的生活有多好。
He needs to know how good my life could have been.
- 伊夫林！艾芙琳！艾芙琳！- 艾芙琳！艾芙琳！
- Evelyn! Evelyn! - Evelyn!
- 嗷！- 你和我在一起吗？
- Ow! - Are you with me?
我以为我被切断了联系。
I thought I was disconnected.
为什么我还在那里？
Why was I still there?
你的思想，就像一个盛水的泥罐。
Your mind, it's like a Clay pot holding water.
每一次跳跃都会打开另一条裂缝。
Every jump opens another crack,
导致东西渗漏。
causing things to leak through.
通过训练，你将学会重新密封这些裂缝。
With training, you will learn to reseal these cracks.
吃吧。你需要能量。
Eat. You need energy.
奶油奶酪。
Cream cheese.
嗯!
Mmm!
在我的宇宙中，牛群被杀光了。
In my universe, the cattle were killed off.
一个许多事情，我们已经失去了
One of the many things we've lost
在我们对Jobu的战争中。
in our war against Jobu.
哦，我的上帝。
Oh, my God.
如果...
What if...
如果我想回去呢？
what if I want to go back?
如果我想回到另一个宇宙呢？
What if I want to go back to the other universe?
关掉它！关掉它，你听到了吗！
Shut it down! Shut it down, you hear me!
- 回来吧！- 好的！好的！好的！
- Come back! - OK! OK! OK!
I... 我回来了！
I... I'm back!
听着，你只是利用
Listen, you're only using
来获得特殊的技能。
the other worlds to acquire special skills.
你明白吗？
Do you understand?
如果你为他们的诱惑所倾倒，
If you fall for their temptations,
你就会招致矛盾和混乱。
you invite contradiction, chaos.
粘土罐可能会碎裂，你可能会死，或者更糟糕。
The Clay pot could shatter and you could die, or far worse.
还有什么能比死亡更糟糕的呢？
What can be worse than death?
我们应该继续前进，直到援军到来。
We should keep moving until reinforcements come.
不，不，不!
No, no, no!
够了，你的粘土罐，奶油奶酪，没有牛。
Enough of your Clay pots, cream cheese, no cows.
现在给我解释一下吧。
Explain it all to me now.
你是对的。
You're right.
在阿尔法宇宙，
In the Alphaverse,
我们开始训练许多年轻的头脑，让他们成为 "跳跃"（Verse Jump）。
we began training many young minds to Verse Jump.
但有一个人是最有天赋的。
But there was one who was far and above the most gifted.
我们的小探险家。
Our little explorer.
你看到了她的潜力...
You saw her potential...
所以你把她推到
so you pushed her
超越了她的极限。
beyond her limit.
警告。不稳定。
Warning. Unstable.
虽然超负荷的头脑通常会死亡。
Though the overloaded mind usually dies,
相反，她的思想被打碎了。
instead her mind was fractured.
警告。不稳定。
Warning. Unstable.
- 心灵断裂。
- Mind fracturing.
现在她的头脑经历了每一个世界，
Now her mind experiences every world,
每一种可能性。
every possibility,
在相同的确切时间。
at the same exact time,
掌握着无限的知识
commanding the infinite knowledge
和多元宇宙的力量。
and power of the multiverse.
现在她看得太多了。
Now she's seen too much,
失去了任何道德感。
lost any sense of morality,
对客观真理的任何信仰。
any belief in objective truth.
她想要什么？
What does she want?
没有人知道。
No-one knows.
我们只知道
All we know
就是她在找你。
is she's looking for you.
嘿，你说过我是错误的那个。
Hey, you said I was the wrong one.
你刚才所做的，改变了我的想法。
What you did back there, it changed my mind.
你真是不可思议。
You were incredible.
韦蒙德。
Waymond.
当然了。
Of course.
伊夫林！回来吧！
Evelyn! Come back!
艾芙琳！跳到另一个战斗宇宙！
Evelyn! Jump to another combat universe!
- 嗯？- 试试自己尿尿吧!
- Huh? - Try peeing yourself!
- 小便？- 这总是一个很好的跳板！
- Pee? - It's always a good jumping pad!
来吧，醒醒！醒醒吧！
Come on, wake up! Wake up!
你对我做了什么？
What did you do to me?
你在我额头上钉了什么东西吗？
Did you staple something to my forehead?
没有，我什么都没做。你自己做的！
No! I didn't do anything. You did it yourself!
- 我们叫了支援吗？- 我没有对自己下手！
- Did we call for backup? - I did not do it to myself!
- 你打电话了吗？- 这上面有血迹！
- Did you call? - It has blood on it!
我们已经拘留了袭击者。没有要求支援。
We've detained the assailants. No backup was requested.
你们这是在浪费一趟时间。收到吗？
You guys are wasting a trip up. Copy?
哦，不！她发现了我们。
Oh, no! She found us.
我说，你收到吗？
I said, do you copy?
清除他们。
Clear them.
# 雨天... #
♪ Rainy day... ♪
? 去远方... ?
♪ Go far away... ♪
乔伊？
Joy?
你为什么看起来这么傻？
Why do you look so stupid?
夫人。
Ma'am.
你和... 你的猪不能在这里。
You and... your pig can't be here.
? 孤独的夜晚... ?
♪ Lonely nights... ♪
是我不能在这里... ...
Is it that I can't be here...
还是说我不能来...
or that I'm not allowed...
- 哼！- ...来这里？
- Huh! - ..to be here?
嘿！
Hey!
好吧...
OK...
手放在我可以看到的地方。
Hands where I can see them.
你看，我可以在这里实际存在。
See, I can physically be here.
但你想说的是
But what you meant to say
是你不允许我在这里。
is you're not allowing me to be here.
手放在你的背后。来吧。
Hands behind your back. Come on.
韦蒙！
Waymond!
你要让我穿过你？
You're going to make me walk through you?
是啊，可爱。我也不能让你这么做。
Yeah, cute. I can't let you do that either.
对，又是 "不能"！
Yeah, again with the 'can't'!
你看，我觉得你不明白
See, I don't think you understand
这个词的含义。
the meaning of that word.
- 看，我可以穿过你。- 警官倒下了！
- See, I can walk through you. - Officer down!
- 不，不！不要开枪。- 手放在头上。
- No, no! Don't shoot. - Hands on your head.
像这样吗？
Like this?
- 韦蒙。醒醒吧！醒醒吧！- 爸爸！
- Waymond. Wake up! Wake up! - Daddy!
哦，不！
Oh, no!
哦，该死。
Oh, shit.
- 唉！- 哦！
- Ugh! - Oh!
- 不！- 哦，不！
- No! - Oh, no!
别担心，艾芙琳。
Don't worry, Evelyn.
- 不, 不! 哦，上帝！- 这是...
- No, no! Oh, God! - It's...
嗯！有机的。
Mmm! Organic.
啊... ... !
Arggh...!
哦，我的上帝。
Oh, my God.
你...
You...
你是Juju Toobootie。
You're Juju Toobootie.
韦蒙所说的 "大恶 "是......。
The "Great Evil" Waymond was talking about is...
在我的欢乐中？
in my Joy?
不要参与。
Don't engage.
不能跟她讲道理。
She can't be reasoned with.
哦...
Oh...
是你。
It's you.
你是我女儿的原因
You're the reason my daughter
不再打电话了
doesn't call anymore,
为什么她从大学辍学
why she dropped out of college
并得到了纹身。
and gets tattoos.
啊！你
Aww!
你...
You...
是她认为自己是同性恋的原因。
are why she thinks she is gay.
啊!
Ah!
我很抱歉。
I'm so sorry.
你还在纠结于这个事实
You're still hung up on the fact
我喜欢这个世界上的女孩？
that I like girls in this world?
宇宙...
The universe...
比你意识到的要大得多。
is so much bigger than you realise.
嗯？
Huh?
好吧！
OK!
不，不，不，不，不，不，不，不！
No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no!
停！
Stop!
- 哼！- 不要让我和你打。
- Huh! - Don't make me fight you.
我真的很厉害。
I am really good.
我不相信你。
I don't believe you.
好吧，好吧。
OK, OK.
不错。
Nice.
你自己尿了。
You peed yourself.
不，艾芙琳，你没有被锁在里面！
No, Evelyn, you're not locked in!
哦！
Oh!
嗯。
Hmm.
她在哪里跳的？
Where did she jump?
嗯，她离开了该死的地图。
Um, she's off the damn map.
? 扇动你的手
♪ Flap your hands
? 我的手... ?
♪ My hands... ♪
她似乎是在一个宇宙中
She appears to be in a universe
在那里每个人都有...
where everyone has...
热狗而不是手指。
hot dogs instead of fingers.
我的意思是，不管我看到多少次
I mean, it just doesn't matter
我看到多少次，我都很感动。
how many times I see it, I'm so moved.
哦，你别闹了!
Oh, you stop it!
一个进化的分支
An evolutionary branch
在人类的解剖学中？
in the anatomy of the human race?
这样的跳跃
A jump like that
就会把大多数人烧死。
would've fried most people.
就像我说的...
Like I said...
她不是大多数人。
she's not most people.
不要... 你为什么要这样对待我？
Don't... Why are you treating me like this?
前一分钟，你是如此的温暖，
One minute, you're so warm,
然后一分钟，你就变得又冷又可怕。
then one minute, you're cold and awful.
这真是疯了！
This is crazy!
你开始明白了。
You're starting to get it.
你要去哪里？
Where are you gonna go?
呃！
Ugh!
你知道，在我见过的所有埃弗林中... ...
You know, of all the Evelyns I've seen...
你绝对是一个更有趣的人。
you're definitely one of the more interesting ones.
你想从我这里得到什么？
What do you want from me?
在这里。
Here.
让我帮你打开你的思想，嗯？
Let me help you open up your mind, huh?
嗯？
Hmm?
- 哦！--这里。
- Oh! - Here.
打开吧。
Open up.
没事的。
It's OK.
偷看一下。
Take a peek.
哦，该死。
Oh, shit.
那是什么？
What is that?
有一天我觉得很无聊
I got bored one day
我把所有东西都放在百吉饼上。
and I put everything on a bagel.
所有东西。
Everything.
我所有的希望和梦想，我的旧成绩单。
All my hopes and dreams, my old report cards,
每个品种的狗。
every breed of dog,
每一个在Craigslist上的个人广告。
every last personal ad on craigslist.
芝麻。
Sesame.
罂粟籽。
Poppy seed.
盐。
Salt.
然后它自己倒塌了。
And it collapsed in on itself.
因为，你看，当你真正把
'Cause, you see, when you really put
一切都在一个百吉饼，
everything on a bagel,
它变成了这样。
it becomes this.
来吧。快跑，伊夫林。
Come on. Run, Evelyn.
真相。
The truth.
真相是什么？
What is the truth?
没有什么...
Nothing...
事。
matters.
不，乔伊。
No, Joy.
你不相信这个。
You don't believe that.
感觉很好，不是吗？
Feels nice, doesn't it?
如果什么都不重要...
If nothing matters...
然后你感到所有的痛苦和内疚
then all the pain and guilt you feel
因为你的生活一无所获...
for making nothing of your life...
就会消失。
it goes away.
♪ 被吸食
♪ Sucked
♪ 进入
♪ Into
? 一个百吉饼。 ?
♪ A bagel. ♪
不!
No!
- 阿巴？
- Ah Ba?
我不是你的父亲。
I'm not your father.
至少不是你认识的那个。
At least not the one you know.
我是阿尔法公公。
I am Alpha Gong Gong.
- 哼！- 也不是你！
- Huh! - Not you too!
先生，你在这里做什么？
Sir, what are you doing here?
我们得走了。跟着我就行。
We need to go. Just follow me.
先生，这一切都在我的掌控之中。
Sir, I have this under control.
你又一次故意不听我的话
Again, you deliberately disobey me
并导致另一个人的思想受到影响。
and cause another mind to be compromised.
现在你知道我们必须做什么了。
And now you know what we must do.
不! 请别这样。
No! Please.
她不像我们所见过的任何东西。
She's unlike anything we've seen.
她最终可以阻止Jobu Tupaki。
She could finally stop Jobu Tupaki.
你是说我女儿体内的那个怪物？
You mean the monster that is inside my daughter?
那么，你为什么不早点告诉我？
Well, why didn't you tell me about it earlier?
你们阿尔法人还有什么没有告诉我？
What else are you Alpha people not telling me?
你看到她把那个男人跳死了吗？
Did you see her dance that man to death?
我不可能是你要找的那个艾芙琳。
There is no way I am the Evelyn you are looking for.
不，我看得很清楚。
No, I see it so clearly.
看到什么？
See what?
我什么都不擅长。
I'm no good at anything.
正是如此。
Exactly.
我见过成千上万的伊夫林，
I've seen thousands of Evelyns,
但从来没有一个像你这样的伊夫林。
but never an Evelyn like you.
你有那么多的目标，却从未完成。
You have so many goals you never finished,
你有那么多从未完成的目标，从未遵循的梦想。
dreams you never followed.
你活在你最糟糕的自己身上。
You're living your worst you.
我不能成为最糟糕的人。那个热狗的呢？
I cannot be the worst. What about that hot dog one?
不，你没看到吗？
No. Can't you see?
这里的每一次失败都是在另一个生命中的另一个艾芙琳身上产生的成功
Every failure here branched off into a success
为另一个伊夫林在另一个生活中的成功。
for another Evelyn in another life.
大多数人只有几条重要的
Most people only have a few significant
变化的人生道路。
alternate life paths so close to them.
但你，在这里。
But you, here,
你有能力做任何事
you're capable of anything
因为你在任何事情上都是那么糟糕。
because you're so bad at everything.
当她的头脑已经屈服于这种混乱时，所有的力量有什么用呢？
What good is all that power when her mind
已经屈服于这种混乱，所有的力量又有什么用呢，嗯？
is already succumbing to that chaos, huh?
喂？
Hello?
喂？妈妈，爸爸？发生什么事了？
Hello? Mom, Dad? What's going on?
不，不要回答她。
No. Do not answer her.
这是她的诡计之一。
It's one of her tricks.
先生，我们的读数显示这不是乔布-图帕奇。
Sir, our readings indicate it's not Jobu Tupaki.
但如果她不在这里...
But if she's not here...
哦，该死！
Oh, shit!
不要参与！快跑！快跑!
Do not engage! Run! Run!
在我处理乔布的时候，看着这两个人。
Watch these two here while I deal with Jobu.
我不会为了这个拿阿尔法宇宙的安全冒险的。
I'm not risking the safety of the Alphaverse for this.
让我们离乔伊越远越好。
Get us as far away from Joy as you can.
- 为什么？我保证。
- Why? - I'll be back. I promise.
不，不，不，等等。你为什么不...
No, no, no, wait. Why don't you...
咦？
Huh?
- 喂？
- Hello? - Joy?
- 不，不... 这不是... - 乔伊在这里！
- No, no... That's not... - Joy's here!
- 不，不，不，那不是乔伊。- 喂？
- No, no, no, that's not Joy. - Hello?
- 乔伊？乔伊，我来了。- 让我进去。
- Joy? Joy, I'm coming. - Let me in.
好的，耐心点！这很重。
OK, be patient! This is heavy.
- 乔伊，你为什么在这里？- 我他妈的一点头绪都没有！
- Joy, why are you here? - I have no fucking clue!
- 嘿，温柔的语言！- 到底发生了什么事？
- Hey, gentle language! - Just what is going on?
我敢肯定，这一切都有一个非常好的解释...
I'm sure there's a very good explanation for all of this...
什么他妈的，妈妈？
What the fuck, Mom?!
你他妈的在做什么？
What the fuck are you doing?
但是...她太强大了。
But... she's too powerful.
我们都中风了吗？
Are we all having a stroke?
你们就像木偶一样。你知道吗？傀儡？
You are like puppets. You know? Puppets?
你可以做你通常不能做的事情。
You can do things you normally cannot do.
这就像那部电影。
It's like that movie.
嗯，你... 你... 那部电影...
Um, you... you... That movie...
好吧，你在说什么？
OK, what are you talking about?
- 一部电影？- "Raccaccoonie"！
- A movie? - 'Raccaccoonie'!
- 什么？
- What? - Huh?
"Raccaccoonie"，你知道吗？
'Raccaccoonie', you know?
那部电影里的厨师...
The one with the chef...
他做的食物很差。呸。
And he makes bad food. Phooey.
然后这只浣熊就坐在他头上。
And then this raccoon sit on his head,
哦，控制他，然后他就做了好的食物。
ooh, control him, and then he cooks good food.
你是说 "料理鼠王 "吗？
Do you mean 'Ratatouille'?
鼠来宝》？我喜欢那部电影。
'Ratatouille'? I like that movie.
不，不，不，不，不，不。"Raccaccoonie"!
No. No, no, no, no, no. 'Raccaccoonie'!
和浣熊一起。
With the raccoon.
- 好吧... - 浣熊？
- OK... - Raccoon?
各位，别再编故事了！
Everybody, stop making up sounds!
所以有一个浣熊乔伊，还有一个浣熊我？
So there's a raccoon Joy, and there's a raccoon me?
他们在控制我们？
And they are controlling us?
是的，来自其他宇宙。
Yeah, from the other universes.
- 哦。好的。- 这很有趣，伊夫林。
- Oh. OK. - That's very funny, Evelyn.
好吧，这听起来有点可笑，但这是真的。
OK, it sounds a little bit ridiculous, but it's true.
我向上帝发誓，你...
I swear to God, you...
你是大男子主义的人。
You are macho man.
- 我喜欢这样！- 哦，是的。
- I like that! - Oh, yeah.
嘿，亲爱的，别担心。
Hey, honey, don't worry.
- 爸爸会让你摆脱困境的。- 阿巴？
- Daddy will get you out of this. - Ah Ba?
快点，趁她分心的时候。
Quickly, while she is distracted.
- 不，这只是协议。
- No. - It's only protocol.
这让她少了一个可以进入的宇宙。
It gives her one less universe to access.
天啊...
God...
- 你能不能... - 哦，是贝琪。
- Can you... - Oh, it's Becky.
嗨，贝琪。等一下。
Hi, Becky. Hold on.
你怎么能指望在每个宇宙中都能打败她呢？
How do you expect to defeat her in every universe
如果你甚至不能在一个宇宙中杀死她？
if you can't even kill her in one?
嘿，宝贝儿。
Hey, babe.
她是你的孙女。
She's your granddaughter.
你认为我的感觉如何？
How do you think I feel?
但这是一种牺牲
But this is a sacrifice
是赢得战争的必要条件。
that is necessary to win the war.
好了，我们走吧。
OK, there we go.
你必须这样做。
You must do it.
去吧。
Go.
走吧。
是的，我妈妈把我绑在椅子上。
Yeah, my mom taped me to a chair.
呃，因为有浣熊。
Uh, because of raccoons.
- 好吧，耐心点。- 是的，这是一个很长的故事。
- OK, be patient. - Yeah, it's a long story.
- 爸爸正在努力... - 已经过了一天了。
- Daddy's trying to... - It's been a day.
妈妈？
Mom?
我一点也不喜欢这样。
I don't like this at all.
你在...
What are you...
你在做什么？
what are you doing?
嘿，我差点就成功了。
Hey! I almost had it.
哦，来吧！
Oh, come on!
你已经在她的魔力之下了。
You are already under her spell.
我靠！该死的，他有枪！
Holy shit! Holy shit, he has a gun!
各位，保持冷静！
Everyone, stay calm!
我想现在是时候进行家庭讨论了！
I think it's time for a family discussion!
没事了，没事了，没事了。
It's OK, it's OK, it's OK.
我不会让你杀了她。
I won't let you kill her.
你没看到你的思想正在发生什么吗？
Don't you see what is happening to your mind?
在我的宇宙中。
In my universe,
你把你自己的女儿逼得太紧了，直到你把她弄坏。
you pushed your own daughter too hard until you broke her.
你...
You...
你创造了Jobu Tupaki。
you created Jobu Tupaki.
他的英语什么时候变得这么好了？
When did he get so good at English?
现在我必须阻止你。
Now I must stop you.
否则，这只是一个时间问题
Otherwise, it's only a matter of time
你就会变得和她一样。
before you become just like her.
就像她一样？
Just like her?
- 嗯？- 你他妈的在做什么？
- Huh? - What the fuck are you doing?
艾芙琳，我不认为现在是跳舞的好时机！
Evelyn, I don't think now is a good time to dance!
粑粑。
Baba,
我知道你不同意我的观点。
I know you don't agree with me,
但这是我必须要做的事。
but this is something I have to do.
- 什么... - 这听起来很奇怪。
- What the... - That sounds weird.
不，不，不...
No, no, no...
- 好吧 等等！
- OK. - Wait!
你不知道你会跳到哪里。
You don't know where you'll jump.
够了！
Enough!
警告： 不稳定。
Warning. Unstable.
求你了。
Please.
我不能在黑暗中再失去一个亲人。
I cannot lose another loved one to the darkness.
- 警告。不稳定。- 别担心。你不会的。
- Warning. Unstable. - Don't worry. You won't.
嘿，呃，在那里清理一下，好吗？
Hey, uh, clean up in there, alright?
这里。哦！
Here. Oh!
她在哪里跳的？
Where did she jump?!
对不起，阿巴。
Sorry, Ah Ba.
- 哇！
- Whoa! - OK!
- 来吧，来吧，来吧！- 天哪，妈妈！
- Come on, come on, come on! - Jesus, Mom!
- 那边走！- 哦，不！
- That way! - Oh, no!
- 哦，我的上帝！- 来吧，来吧！
- Oh, my God! - Come on, come on!
- 哦！
- Oh! - No!
警告，心灵分裂。
Warning, mind fracturing.
派出所有在该地区有对应关系的跳伞者。
Send every Jumper with a counterpart in the area.
现在！
Now!
再一次，阿尔法宇宙发现自己
Once again, the Alphaverse finds itself
成为对抗全面混乱的最后一道防线。
as the last line of defence against total chaos.
勇敢点。这个伊夫林和其他人一样顽固。
Be brave. This Evelyn is as stubborn as the others.
她已经让我们别无选择。
She has given us no choice.
我们必须在她成为另一个Jobu Tupaki之前杀死她。
We must kill her before she becomes another Jobu Tupaki.
- 乐乐。- 哦，什么？
- Joy. - Oh, what?
乔伊... 乐乐...
Joy... Joy...
我知道你有这些感觉。
I know you have these feelings,
让你如此悲伤的感觉。
feelings that make you so sad.
这让你只是......只是想放弃。
That makes you just... just want to give up.
这不是你的错。
It's not your fault.
不是你的错。
Not your fault.
我知道。
I know.
这是... ... 这是她。
It's... it's her.
Juju Chewbacca。
Juju Chewbacca.
她把你的灵魂...
She has your soul...
在她的手掌上。
in the palm of her hand.
你在说什么呢？
What are you talking about?
我唯一能打败她来救你的方法...
The only way I can defeat her to save you...
就是变得像她一样。
is to become like her.
伊夫林！
Evelyn!
你的女儿已经无法挽救了。
Your daughter is beyond saving.
而且很快你也会这样。
And soon you will be too.
你的时间到了。
Your time is up.
找到你的跳板。
Find your jumping pads.
♪ 万福玛丽亚... ♪
♪ Ave Maria... ♪
妈妈？妈妈？
Mom? Mom?
我想你把事情推得太远了。
I think you're pushing things too far.
或者说还不够远。
Or not far enough.
哦，我的上帝！哦，我的天啊！
Oh, my God! Oh, my God!
伊夫林？
Evelyn?
- 呃！- 哦，我的上帝。
- Ugh! - Oh, my God.
哦!
Oh!
你在做什么？
What are you doing?!
妈妈！
Mom!
Arggh!
哦！
Ohh!
我的... ... 该死。
Holy... shit.
他死了吗？
Is he dead?
看，没死。走！
See, not dead. Go!
- 这绝对不是... - 快点，请。快走！
- That's definitely not... - Hurry up, please. Go quick!
好了，来吧，伙计们。
OK, come on, guys.
爸爸，快走！
Dad, go!
哦，我的天。
Oh, my God.
我的宝贝想出去走走吗？
Does my baby want to go for a walk?
哟！
Yow!
不！
No!
哦，约翰尼！哦！
Oh, Johnny! Oh!
橙汁汽水？
Orange soda?
- 嗯？- 她在做什么？
- Huh? - What is she doing?
我想当她做一些奇怪的事情时
I think when she does something weird
就会帮助她战斗，给她力量。
it helps her fight, it gives her power.
对不起，宝贝。
Sorry, baby.
再问她要一个。
Ask her for another one.
不！约翰尼！
No! Johnny!
煎蛋？
Fried egg?
你... 婊子。
You... bitch.
走！
Go!
嗯？
Huh?
哦...
Oh...
伊夫林，如果你不站出来，
Evelyn, if you don't step up,
我就把你的一些班次给乍得。
I'm giving some of your shifts to Chad.
是啊！
Yeah!
- 哦，我的上帝！- 哦，好样的！
- Oh, my God! - Oh, good one!
我拍到一张照片！
I got a picture!
走吧。
Go.
停止...
Stop...
- 嗯？发生了什么事？- 你停下！
- Huh? What happened? - You stop!
我认为他们失去了他们的...
I think they lost their...
- 别说了！- ...力量？
- Stop it! - ..powers?
先生？
Sir?
我需要另一个跳板。
I am gonna need another jumping pad.
收到的信息。完毕。
Received information. Over.
我想她需要再做一些奇怪的事情。
I think she needs to do something weird again.
他在做什么？
What's he doing?
哦，我的上帝。他想把它插进自己的屁股里。
Oh, my God. He's trying to stick it in his butt.
不！
No!
- 不，不，不！ - 啊，不！
- No, no, no! - Ah... No!
啊，艾芙琳，做跳绳！
Ah, Evelyn, do jumping Jacks!
这一点都不奇怪。
That's not weird at all.
嗯......给他一巴掌！
Um... Slap him!
不，不，不，不！
No, no, no, no!
妈妈，你就对着他的鼻子吹吧！
Mom, just blow on his nose!
什么？
What?
这将使他不由自主地
It'll make him involuntarily
尖叫和发出奇怪的声音。
scream and do weird noises.
相信她，艾芙琳！这真的很奇怪。
Trust her, Evelyn! It's really weird.
哇，妈妈真的很厉害。
Wow, Mom is really good.
哼！
Huh!
对不起。
Sorry.
哦！
Oh!
啊！
Arggh!
Ahh!
达到了心理承受能力。
Reaching mental capacity.
达到心理承受能力。
我的妈呀！
Holy shit!
- 嗷！- 我很抱歉，艾芙琳。
- Ow! - I'm sorry, Evelyn.
- 思想崩溃了。- 我们会一起死的。
- Mind fracturing. - We'll die together.
小指头... 啊！
Pinky... Arggh!
- 抓住她。我看到她了。- 我们走吧！
- Get her. I see her. - Let's go!
伊夫林！
Evelyn!
艾芙琳。艾芙琳！
Evelyn. Evelyn!
哇，哇！
Whoa, whoa!
不需要解释。
No need to explain.
我一直在观察你。
I have been watching you.
你回来了！
You're back!
你看到我有多厉害了吗？
Did you see how good I am?
我一定要做到这一点。
I'm gonna do it.
我要打败那个乔布-图帕奇。
I am going to defeat that Jobu Tupaki.
嘿，你说对了她的名字。
Hey. You got her name right.
艾芙琳，你所做的是疯狂的，鲁莽的。
Evelyn, what you're doing is crazy, reckless.
你那愚蠢的计划，以某种方式拯救你的女儿
Your stupid plan to somehow save your daughter
已经成功地激怒了多元宇宙中的每个人。
has managed to piss off everyone in the multiverse.
但它可能会成功。
But it just might work.
什么？什么？
What? What?
我只希望我可以在那里
I only wish I could be there
看到你完成这个。
to see you finish this.
你是什么意思，你没有看到我完成？
What do you mean, you don't see me finish?
我很感激
I'm grateful
机会足够好
that chance was kind enough
让我们有这最后的时光在一起。
to let us have these last few moments together.
阿尔法-韦蒙德？
Alpha Waymond?
发生了什么事？
What happened?
我又是莱孔-韦蒙德吗？
Was I Raccoon Waymond again?
浣熊韦蒙德已经死了。
Raccoon Waymond is dead.
那是莱孔-乔伊吗？
Is that Raccoon Joy?
我得到它吗？
Am I getting it?
我可以阻止你，Jobu ...
I can to stop you, Jobu...
现在，我已经达到了我的全部潜力。
now that I am reaching my full potential.
哦，你还是看不清发生了什么。
Oh, you still can't see what's happening.
不，我看得很清楚。
No, I see clearly.
比以前更清楚。
More clearly than ever before.
哦，我的上帝！伊夫林。
Oh, my God! Evelyn.
哦，我的上帝！
Oh, my God!
该死的。如此接近。
Damn it. So close.
艾芙琳？艾芙琳？
Evelyn? Evelyn?
请帮助她。
Please help her.
我很快就会再见到你。
I'll see you again soon.
? 在那里的某个地方
♪ Somewhere out there
? 在所有的噪音中... ?
♪ In all that noise... ♪
不要离开！请帮帮她！
Don't leave! Help her, please!
救命！救命啊！
Help! Help!
她在哪里？
Where is she?
我们的女儿在哪里？
Where's our daughter?
女儿？
Daughter?
? 我们是一家人
♪ We're family
♪ 我们是一家人
♪ We're a family
- ? 烹饪上。- 乍得： ? Culinarily
- ♪ Culinarily. - Chad: ♪ Culinarily
? 现在我们正在做饭... ?
♪ Now we're cooking... ♪
- 哦，Raccaccoonie。- ? 当没有人看'... ♪
- Oh, Raccaccoonie. - ♪ When nobody's lookin'... ♪
我不知道没有你我该怎么办。
I don't know what I'd do without you.
Raccaccoonie？
Raccaccoonie?
是的，我们是一个相当不错的团队。
Yeah, we make a pretty good team.
厨艺方面...
♪ Culinarily... ♪
- 哦，不！
- Oh, no! - Uh...
你... 你不能告诉任何人。
You... you can't tell anyone.
她见得太多了。你知道这意味着什么。
She's seen too much. You know what that means.
- 抓住她！抓住她！- 不，不，我求你了。 不，不！
- Get her! Get her! - No, no, I'm begging you.
- 不，不！抓住她！ 抓住她！
- No, no! - Get her! Get her!
- 不，我... 不，不！
- No, I... No. No! - Please.
- 求你了，抓住她！- 快走！快走吧！
- Get her! - Just go! Just go!
你想要什么？
What do you want?
我想要你。
I want you.
不！
No!
别这样！
Stop that!
哦！
Oh!
- 别过来！
- Oh! - Stay back!
这是不对的！
This is wrong!
- 这是不对的！- 什么，没有错！
- This is wrong! - What? It's not wrong!
I... 我已经迟到了。
I... I'm late.
我可以想任何我想要的胡言乱语，在某个地方...
I can think of whatever nonsense I want and somewhere...
我做到了。
I did it.
嗯？
Huh?
别忘了这些饼干。
Don't forget these cookies.
迪尔德丽小姐非常喜欢它们。
Miss Deirdre really likes them.
来吧。
Come on.
嗨，王夫人。
Hi, Mrs Wang.
嘿，妈妈。那么，关于今天早上...
Hey, Mom. So, about this morning...
- 别再耍花招了。- 什么？
- Enough with your tricks. - What?
- 我知道你在里面。- 哇。
- I know you're in there. - Whoa.
- 离开我的女儿。- 好了！
- Get out of my daughter. - OK!
妈妈，你已经喝醉了吗？
Mom, are you already drunk?
- 嘿，贝琪。- 嗯哼？
- Hey, Becky. - Mmm-hmm?
你能不能去帮我爸搞个派对？
Can you go help my dad with the party?
现在吗？
Now?
- 是的 去吧，贝琪。
- Yeah. - Go, Becky.
去吧，贝琪。 去吧。去吧。
Go. Go.
谢谢你，宝贝。
Thanks, babe.
你看到了这一切，不是吗？
You see it all, don't you?
你可以看到
You can see
所有的事情...
how everything...
只是一个随机的重新排列
is just a random rearrangement
在一个振动的叠加中的粒子的随机重新排列。
of particles in a vibrating superposition.
我不知道你在说什么。
I have no idea what you are talking about.
但我能做到这一点。
But I can do this.
嗯？
Huh?
但是你看...
But you see...
我们所做的一切是如何...
how everything we do...
嗯？
Huh?
都被冲到了海里
Gets washed away in a sea
所有其他的可能性？
of every other possibility?
你无处不在。
You're everywhere.
你就像我一样。
You're like me.
这就对了。
That's right.
我就是你要找的那个人。
I'm the one you're looking for.
我就是那个要打败你的人。
I'm the one who's going to defeat you.
好吧。
OK.
打我。
Hit me.
揍我的脸。
Punch my face.
哦...
Oh...
哦，嗷！嗷！
Oh! Ow! Ow!
- 哦，停下！- 哇。
- Oh, stop! - Wow.
嗨，爸爸。
Hi, Dad.
我们... 我们只是在为今晚的卡拉OK练习。
We're... we're just practising karaoke for tonight.
啦-啦-啦！
♪ La-la-la! ♪
我会处理好的！
I will take care of it!
- 她会照顾它，爸爸。- 走吧。
- She'll take care of it, Dad. - Go.
- 亲爱的，你还好吗？
- Honey, you OK? - It's OK.
- 走吧！- 是的，我只是倒在了沙发上。
- Go! - Yeah, I just fell on the couch.
走吧！
Go!
好的。
OK.
哦。
Oh.
- 嗷... - 他是如此甜蜜。
- Ow... - He's so sweet.
好的。
OK.
嘿，嘿，伙计！
Hey, hey, buddy!
如果你不想和我打，那么...
If you don't want to fight me, then...
- 为什么 为什么什么？
- Why? - Why what?
什么... 这一切是为了什么？
What... what's all this for?
我为什么要找你？
Why was I looking for you?
是的。
Yeah.
坐下来。
Sit down.
坐下来，吃点东西。
Sit down, grab a snack,
让自己舒服点，嗯？
make yourself comfortable, huh?
- 哦，嘿，你还好吗？
- Oh, hey, you OK? - OK.
嗯。我们可以加快这个速度。
Mmm. We can speed this up.
坐在裂缝上。
Sit on the crack.
坐在沙发的缝隙上，好吗？
Sit on the crack of the couch, OK?
舒服点。
Get comfortable.
百吉饼。
Bagel.
拜托，我不关心百吉饼。
Please, I don't care about the bagel.
我不关心阿尔法宇宙。
I don't care about the Alphaverse.
我只关心我的乔伊。
I only care about my Joy.
把我的女儿还给我
Give me back my daughter
我就永远不打扰你了。
and I'll leave you alone forever.
对不起！我不知道。不可以。
Sorry! No can do.
为什么不行？
Why not?
我就是你的女儿。你的女儿就是我。
I am your daughter. Your daughter is me.
每个版本的乔伊都是乔布-图帕奇。
Every version of Joy is Jobu Tupaki.
- 你不能把我们分开。- 不能。
- You can't separate us. - No.
我已经感受到了你女儿所感受到的一切。
I have felt everything your daughter has felt.
我知道那种快乐...
And I know the joy...
和有你做我母亲的痛苦。
and the pain of having you as my mother.
那么你知道我会做...
Then you know I would do...
只为她、为你做正确的事。
Only do the right thing for her, for you.
正确 "是一个由害怕的人发明的小盒子
'Right' is a tiny box invented by people who are afraid
我知道被困在这个盒子里是什么感觉。
and I know what it feels like to be trapped inside that box.
妈妈...
Mom...
不，不是这样的。
No, it's not like that.
是公公。
It's Gong Gong.
他是不同的一代。
He's a different generation.
你不用再躲在他身后了。
You don't have to hide behind him anymore.
你应该感到宽慰。
You should feel relieved.
百吉饼会让你看到事物的真实面目。
The bagel will show you the true nature of things.
你会从那个盒子里解放出来，就像我一样。
You'll be free from that box, just like me.
不，不，我不像你。
No, no, I'm not like you.
你还年轻，你的思想总是在变化。
You're young and your mind is always changing.
我仍然知道我是谁。
I still know who I am.
你不知道你做了什么。
You have no idea what you've done.
你会永远停留在这样的状态。
You're stuck like this forever.
不，我要和我的乔伊一起回去。
No, I'm going back with my Joy,
回到我的家庭，过我的生活。
to my family, to live my life.
一个快乐的生活。
A happy life.
好的。
OK.
祝你好运。
Good luck with that.
非常感谢你的到来。
Thank you so much for coming.
谢谢你。感谢你的父亲。
Thank you. Thank your father.
一直以来...
All this time...
我找你不是为了杀你。
I wasn't looking for you so I could kill you.
我只是在寻找一个能看到我所看到的东西的人。
I was just looking for someone who could see what I see.
感受我的感受。
Feel what I feel.
而那个人...
And that someone...
就是你。
is you.
艾芙琳！
Evelyn!
- 你还活着！- 不可能的。
- You're alive! - Impossible.
- 喂，王夫人？
- Hello? - Mrs Wang?
你... 你在哪里？
Where... where are you?
我的意思是，你甚至没有出现在你的约会上？
I mean, to not even show up for your appointment?!
闭嘴吧。
Shut up.
你刚才说什么？
What did you just say?
我说闭嘴。
I said shut up.
你无关紧要。
You don't matter.
不管我做了什么，我很抱歉。
Whatever I did, I'm sorry.
什么都不重要。
Nothing matters.
王夫人！
Mrs Wang!
你会有大麻烦的！
You are gonna be in serious trouble!
你明白吗？
Do you understand?
对于你不尊重...
For you to disrespect...
新年快乐！
Happy New Year!
又是一年，嗯？
Another year, hmm?
假装我们知道我们在做什么。
Pretending we know what we're doing,
但实际上，我们只是在绕圈圈。
but, really, we're just going around in circles.
洗衣服和纳税。
Doing laundry and taxes,
洗衣服和缴税。
and laundry and taxes.
- 没有更多的跑步。- 请原谅我。
- No more running. - Excuse me.
业主们在哪里？哦。
Where are the owners? Oh.
你们在这里。王先生和王太太。
There you are. Mr and Mrs Wang.
你们让我别无选择，只能授权扣押
You have left me no option but to authorise the seizure
你的个人和你的商业资产。
of your personal and your business assets.
- 你们必须搬出... - 等等，艾芙琳！
- You have to vacate... - Wait, Evelyn!
这实在是太好了，你知道吗？
It's just so good, you know?
你在做什么？不！不！
What are you doing? No! No!
我的上帝，乍得，我告诉你，她不能被信任！
My God, Chad, I told you she couldn't be trusted!
艾芙琳，拜托！冷静下来。
Evelyn, please! Calm down.
在48小时内或...
Within 48 hours or...
一切...
Everything...
呃！
Ugh!
你在做什么？
What are you doing?
没有一个时刻会在
Not a single moment will go by
没有任何其他的宇宙
without every other universe
都在呼唤着你的注意。
screaming for your attention.
永远不会完全存在。
Never fully there.
只是一生的...
Just a lifetime of...
不，不！
No, no!
破碎的时刻。
Fractured moments.
Raccaccoonie!
矛盾和混乱...
Contradictions and confusion...
- 放开我！- 乍得，别忘了我。
- Get off me! - Chad, don't forget about me.
这里有文件。
Here are the papers.
- 哦，哦，警官？- 好的，好的。
- Oh! Oh, officer? - OK, OK.
只有几个时间点
With only a few specks of time
任何事情都是有意义的。
where anything actually makes any sense.
我一直很讨厌这个地方。
I've always hated this place.
Raccaccoonie！
Raccaccoonie!
乍得！
Chad!
放开我！快滚开！
Get off me! Get off!
伊夫林，为什么呢！
Evelyn, why?!
你知道为什么我真的建立了百吉饼吗？
Do you know why I actually built the bagel?
这不是为了摧毁一切。
It wasn't to destroy everything.
而是为了摧毁我自己。
It was to destroy myself.
我想看看如果我进去了，我能不能最终逃脱？
I wanted to see if I went in, could I finally escape?
比如，真正的死亡。
Like, actually die.
至少这样的话...
At least this way...
我不需要独自完成。
I don't have to do it alone.
你没在听。
You're not listening.
这已经超出了我的能力范围...
This is out of my league...
布伦纳法官签署了...
Judge Brenner signed...
好吧，原谅我！对不起，王先生。
Well, excuse me! Excuse me, Mr Wang.
我认识的每个人都在经历一段艰难的时期。
Every person I know is going through a hard time.
- 这是个艰难的时刻... - 伊夫林！
- It's a hard time... - Evelyn!
回来吧。
Come back.
我愚蠢的丈夫。
My silly husband.
可能会让事情变得更糟。
Probably making things worse.
别理它。
Ignore it.
好了，你可以让她走了。
OK, you can let her go.
你，让她走吧。没事的。好的！
You, let her go. It's OK. Yes!
谢谢你。
Thank you.
怎么放？这是不可能的。
How? That's impossible.
这只是一种统计学上的必然性。
It's just a statistical inevitability.
这没什么特别的。
It's nothing special.
我不知道。
I don't know.
我刚刚和她谈过。
I just talked to her.
求你了！
Please!
我们能不能... ... 我们能不能不吵架？
Can we... can we just stop fighting?
我知道你们都在吵架
I know you are all fighting
因为你们很害怕，很困惑。
because you're scared and confused.
我也很迷惑。
I'm confused too.
整天...
All day...
我不知道到底发生了什么。
I don't know what the heck is going on.
但不知为何...
But somehow...
这感觉就像这都是我的错。
this feels like it's all my fault.
我不知道。
I don't know.
我唯一知道的是...
The only thing I do know...
就是我们必须要有爱心。
is that we have to be kind.
求你了。
Please.
善待...
Be kind...
特别是当我们不知道发生了什么的时候。
especially when we don't know what's going on.
嘿，伊夫林！
Hey, Evelyn!
贝果。
Bagel.
艾芙琳...
Evelyn...
你还是可以转过身来，避免这一切。
You can still turn around and avoid all this.
请...
Please...
善待自己。
be kind.
太晚了，韦蒙。
It's too late, Waymond.
别这么说。
Don't say that.
你看到了吗？
Did you see that?
哦，哦，哦，哦！哦！
Ooh! Ooh-ooh! Ooh!
- 哼！找到它了！- 看看这个！
- Huh! Found it! - Check this!
这是什么歌？
What song is this?
谢谢。谢谢你的到来。
Thanks. Thank you for coming.
这很有趣。
That's very funny.
- 是的，这就是它？- 是的！
- Yeah, that's it? - Yeah!
我也很抱歉。
I'm sorry too.
哦！
Oh!
太可爱了！
So cute!
来吧，伊夫林。
Come on, Evelyn.
来吧。
Come on.
哦。
Oh.
我明白了。
I get it.
感觉是件好事。
Feeling a good thing.
你得到了你的希望。
You got your hopes up.
所以我在这里为你节省一些时间。
So I'm here to save you some time.
最终...
Eventually...
这一切都会消失。
that all just goes away.
只是消失了。
Just goes away.
来吧。
Come on.
我不在乎你是否和我一起去。
I don't care if you come with me.
享受你的生活。
Enjoy your life.
唉！
Ugh!
伊夫林！艾芙琳，拜托！
Evelyn! Evelyn, please!
不要再这样了！
No more!
我不想伤害你。
I don't want to hurt you.
乔伊，跟我回去吧。
Joy, come back with me.
乔伊! 乔伊！
Joy! Joy!
我那愚蠢的丈夫对你说了什么？
What did my silly husband say to you?
他告诉我你的情况。
He told me about your situation.
我想起了我丈夫给我送文件的时候。
I remembered when my husband served me papers.
我开着他的起亚Forte穿过我邻居的厨房。
I drove his Kia Forte through my neighbour's kitchen.
哼!
Huh!
但你知道我怎么说吗？
But you know what I say?
这就是所谓的，"像我们这样不可爱的母狗......"
It's called, "Unlovable bitches like us..."
"让世界运转起来。"
"Make the world go 'round."
不要停止演奏。
Don't stop playing.
为我演奏一些东西。
Play something for me.
那不是真的。
That's not true.
- 你不是不可爱的人。- 你不是不可爱的！
- You're not unlovable. - You're not unlovable!
你在说什么呢？
What are you talking about?
总有一些东西是值得爱的。
There is always something to love.
即使在一个愚蠢的，愚蠢的宇宙中
Even in a stupid, stupid universe
我们有热狗做手指的地方，
where we have hot dogs for fingers,
我们的脚也会变得非常好。
we'd get very good with our feet.
哦！你看？
Oh!
- 看到了吗？- 好了。
- See? - OK.
我没什么感觉。
I feel nothing.
I... 我觉得...
I... I feel...
我感觉到...
I feel...
不要让她阻止乔布！
Don't let her stop Jobu!
开火！
Open fire!
太蠢了！
So stupid!
伊夫林？
Evelyn?
你在做什么？
What are you doing?
我在学着像你一样战斗。
I'm learning to fight like you.
你知道吗, 艾芙琳, 我妻子
You know, Evelyn, my wife
曾经使用过这种完全相同的香水。
used to wear that exact same perfume,
上帝保佑她的灵魂。
God rest her soul.
这些都是直接的迹象
These are direct indications
这些都是直接的迹象，说明神经系统受到了一些冲击。
that there's some impingement of the nervous system.
只要有一点帮助，
With a little bit of help,
我们可以把事情看得很清楚。
we could be seeing things nice and straight.
你可能会觉得有点酸痛。
You might feel a little sore,
但一切看起来都很好。
but everything is looking pretty good.
谢谢你。
Thank you.
在那里打扫一下，好吗？
Clean up in there, alright?
哈!
Hah!
你把一切都从我身边带走了。
You took everything away from me.
我很抱歉。
I'm sorry.
拉卡科尼教了我很多东西！
Raccaccoonie taught me so much!
I... 我甚至不知道
I... I didn't even know
如何煮鸡蛋
how to boil an egg
他却教我如何在锅铲上旋转。
and he taught me how to spin it on a spatula.
我一个人很无用。
I'm useless alone.
我们都是孤独的无用之人。
We're all useless alone.
好在你并不孤单。
It's a good thing you're not alone.
哦!
Oh!
我们去救你的傻浣熊吧。
Let's go rescue your silly raccoon.
哦，我们要去做！
Oh, we're gonna do it!
Arggh!
哦，嗬，嗬！
Oh-ho-ho!
别挡路！
Get out of the way!
韦蒙！
Waymond!
看到了吗？
See?
这只是一个时间问题
It's only a matter of time
一切都会平衡的。
before everything balances itself out.
- 来吧，来吧，来吧！- 我做不到。
- Come on, come on, come on! - I can't.
我很抱歉，Raccaccoonie！我很抱歉！
I'm sorry, Raccaccoonie! I'm sorry!
伊夫林，让她去吧。
Evelyn, let her go.
但她原来很固执。
But she turned out to be stubborn,
漫无目的，一塌糊涂。
aimless, a mess.
就像她母亲一样。
Just like her mother.
但现在我明白了。
But now I see.
她是个烂摊子也没关系。
It's OK that she's a mess.
因为就像我一样...
Because just like me...
嗯。
Huh.
好吧，也许你在这个宇宙中赢了，
Well, maybe you win in this universe,
但在另一个时代...
but in another time...
我打败了你！
I beat you!
哦！
Ohh!
或者我们打成平手！
Or we tie!
或者我们只是...
Or we just...
闲逛。
hang around.
好了，乔伊，听着。
OK, Joy, listen.
因为这一切都只是一个毫无意义的
Because it's all just a pointless
swirling bucket of bullshit.
哼！
Huh!
那个百吉饼是我们最终找到和平的地方，伊夫林。
That bagel is where we finally find peace, Evelyn.
别再叫我伊夫林了！
Stop calling me Evelyn!
I
是。
Am.
你的
Your
你的母亲！
mother!
阿巴？
Ah Ba?
真的吗？
Seriously?
你能不能...
Can you please just...
别闹了！
stop?!
妈妈。
Mom.
就......就停下来。
Just... just stop.
对你有好处。你正在想办法解决你的问题。
Good for you. You're figuring your shit out.
这很好。我真的，真的为你高兴。
And that's great. I'm really, really happy for you.
但我...
But I'm...
我累了。
I'm tired.
我不想再受伤了。
I don't want to hurt anymore.
由于某些原因，当我和你在一起时，它只是...
And for some reason when I'm with you, it just...
它只是伤害了我们两个人。
it just hurts the both of us.
所以我们还是分道扬镳吧，好吗？
So let's just go our separate ways, OK?
让我走吧。
Just let me go.
好的。
OK.
等等。
Wait.
你越来越胖了。
You are getting fat.
而且你从不给我打电话
And you never call me
即使我们有一个家庭计划。
even though we have a family plan.
- 什么，而且是免费的。
- What? - And it's free.
你只有在需要的时候才会来找我。
You only visit when you need something.
你有一个纹身，我不关心
And you got a tattoo and I don't care
如果它应该是代表我们的家庭。
if it's supposed to represent our family.
你知道我讨厌刺青。
You know I hate tattoos.
在所有我可以去的地方中，
And of all the places I could be,
我为什么要在这里和你在一起？
why would I want to be here with you?
是的，你是对的。
Yes, you're right.
这没有意义。
It doesn't make sense.
伊夫林！
Evelyn!
让她说完。
Let her finish.
也许就像你说的那样。
Maybe it's like you said.
也许外面有什么东西
Maybe there is something out there,
一些新的发现
some new discovery
会让我们觉得
that will make us feel
像更小的狗屎。
like even smaller pieces of shit.
一些能解释为什么
Something that explains why
你仍然去寻找我
you still went looking for me
通过这一切的噪音。
through all of this noise.
以及为什么。
And why,
无论发生什么事。
no matter what,
我还是想和你在一起。
I still want to be here with you.
我将永远...
I will always...
总是...
always...
想和你在一起。
want to be here with you.
那又怎样？你...
So what? You...
你就这样无视其他一切？
You're just gonna ignore everything else?
你可以是任何东西，任何地方。
You could be anything, anywhere.
为什么不去一个你的...
Why not go somewhere where your...
在那里你的女儿不仅仅是...
where your daughter is more than just...
这个？
this?
在这里，我们得到的一切
Here, all we get
是一些时间的斑点
are a few specks of time
这一切都有意义。
where any of this actually makes any sense.
那么我将珍惜
Then I will Cherish
这几个时间的斑点。
these few specks of time.
你按下按钮。
You push the button.
是的，你去了。
Yeah, there you go.
我觉得我是14岁。
I feel like I'm 14.
是啊。
Yeah.
你是个疯女人！
You're a crazy woman!
要了解一个人就得了解一个人。
Takes one to know one.
我很抱歉，Raccaccoonie！我很抱歉！
I'm sorry, Raccaccoonie! I'm sorry!
- 你在做什么？- 抓住我的头发。
- What are you doing? - Grab my hair.
他说什么了？
What did he say?
? 我们是一家人... ?
♪ We're a family... ♪
? 家庭... ?
♪ Family... ♪
这真是太尴尬了。
This is so awkward.
这是尴尬的，对不对？
This is awkward, right?
你还想办你的派对吗？
Do you still want to do your party?
我们可以做任何我们想做的事。
We can do whatever we want.
什么都无所谓。
Nothing matters.
好了，我们现在肯定要迟到了，伙计们。
OK, we're definitely late now, guys.
你必须把这些都带来吗？
Do you have to bring all these?
嗯，嗯。
Mmm-hmm.
这也需要放在袋子里。
That needs to go in the bag too.
税收很糟糕。
Taxes suck.
谢谢你送我一程，贝基
Thank you for the ride, Becky!
嘿，这很好。
Hey, it's good.
嗯，嗯。你得到这个，好吗？
Mmm-hmm. You got this, OK?
- 贝基？- 我之后再给你打电话。
- Becky? - I'll call you after.
你需要留点头发。
You need to grow your hair.
哇。
Wow.
我以后再打给你！
I'll call you later!
快点，快点！
Hurry, hurry!
我得去尿尿。等一下。
I gotta pee. Hold on.
好的。快点。
OK. Hurry.
好的。是的。
OK. Yes.
我很高兴地说，我确实认为
I am happy to say I do think
事情好转了。
things are better.
这是......这是一个进步。
This is... this is an improvement.
而且我很高兴你听了。
And I'm glad that you listened.
但我们有一个问题
But we have a problem
因为你听了，但你没有听
because you listened, but you didn't listen
而这与附表C有关。
and that has to do with the Schedule C.
你看，你做了...
You see, you did...
伊夫林！你听到我说的了吗？
Evelyn! Did you hear me?
对不起。你说什么？
Sorry. What did you say?
♪ 这是一种生活
♪ This is a life
♪ 摆脱命运的束缚
♪ Free from destiny
♪ 不仅仅是我们播种的东西
♪ Not only what we sow
# 不仅仅是我们所展示的
♪ Not only what we show
# 哦
♪ Ooh
# 这就是生活
♪ This is a life
# 每个可能性
♪ Every possibility
# 从命运中解放出来
♪ Free from destiny
# 我选择你，你选择我
♪ I choose you and you choose me
# 不仅是我们播种的东西
♪ Not only what we sow
♪ 每个空间和每个时间
♪ Every space and every time
♪ 不仅仅是我们所展示的
♪ Not only what we show
♪ 我们所知道的
♪ What we know
♪ 这是一束光
♪ This is a light
♪ 许多生命本可以是这样的
♪ Many lives that could've been
♪ 从熵中解放出来
♪ Free from entropy
? 纠缠在一起，直到永远
♪ Entangled for eternity
? 不仅仅是手和脚趾
♪ Not only hands and toes
♪ 不仅仅是我们所知道的
♪ Not only what we've known
♪ 我们发现
♪ We find
♪ 这个生命
♪ This life
♪ 不知何故
♪ Somehow
? 好吧
♪ Alright
? 这是一种生活
♪ This is a life
? 缓慢和突然的奇迹
♪ Slow and sudden miracles
? 其他世界的看法
♪ View of other worlds
? 从我们的窗台
♪ From our windowsills
♪ 带着重量
♪ With the weight
？ 永恒的？
♪ Of eternity
♪ 以光的速度
♪ At the speed of light
? 这是一种生活
♪ This is a life
? 这就是我们的生活。 ?
♪ This is our life. ♪
♪ 我爱你，我爱你
♪ I love you, I love you
? 我爱你，我爱你
♪ 我爱你，我爱你
♪ I love you, I love you
# 我爱你，我爱你 # # I love you, I love you #
? 我爱你
♪ I love you
? 我爱
♪ I love
? 你
♪ You
? 哦！ ?
♪ Ohh! ♪